machinelearningmastery.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy

## Who we are

We are Machine Learning Mastery Pty. Ltd.

Our website address is: https://machinelearningmastery.com.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

We collect name, email address and message from contact forms in order to respond to queries.

The resulting submission of contact forms are generally not shared.

### Product reviews and testimonials

We may collect name, email address and a product review or testimonial.

Your name, photograph, and review or testimonial may be shared on this website.

If your review or testimonial is posted on the website, you can request that it be removed at any time.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Hosting

This website is hosted with WPEngine.

As part of hosting, some information such as IP address may be logged when visiting this website. This may be used to detect errors or attacks against the website or hosting platform.

You can learn more about WPEngine’s privacy policy here: https://wpengine.com/legal/privacy/

### Analytics

Google Analytics is used to record website visitor statistics.

This may be used in aggregate to learn more about what content is interesting or useful to visitors.

You can learn more about Google’s privacy policy here: https://policies.google.com/privacy

### Amazon Associates Program

Machine Learning Mastery is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

Links to books listed on Amazon are provided for information purposes.

You can learn more about Amazon’s privacy policy here: https://amazon.com/privacy

### Email Marketing Automation

The Leadpages and Drip email automation software services are used.

We collect your email address if you opt-in to email marketing automation.

This email address will be used to send you educational information as well as special offers and promotions related to your interests.

You can learn more about Drip’s privacy policy here: https://www.drip.com/privacy

You can learn more about LeadPages privacy policy here: https://www.leadpages.net/privacy

### Product Purchases

The Samcart shopping cart, Gumroad shopping cart and Stripe and Paypal payment processors services are used.

When you purchase a product we will collect your name, payment information and related personal information required to complete the purchase. Payment information is verified with payment processors and some meta data from the transaction is stored by the payment processor.

You can learn more about Samcart’s privacy policy here: https://www.samcart.com/privacy-policy/

You can learn more about Gumroad’s privacy policy here: https://gumroad.com/privacy

You can learn more about Stripe’s privacy policy here: https://stripe.com/privacy

You can learn more about PayPal’s privacy policy here: https://www.paypal.com/privacy

## Who we share your data with

A list prepared in good faith of companies/services that data is indirectly or automatically with includes:

  * WPEngine for website hosting.
  * Hosted wordpress software for content management.
  * Amazon S3 for content hosting.
  * Google Analytics for website statistics.
  * Drip for email marketing automation.
  * Lead Pages for email marketing automation.
  * Samcart for shopping cart.
  * Stripe for payment processing.
  * PayPal for payment processing.

Some personal information may be shared with employees or contractors of Machine Learning Mastery Pty. Ltd. toward meeting legal, financial or related obligations, not limited to accountants and lawyers.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

If you subscribe to an email marketing campaign, your personal information will be retained indefinitely.

If you make a product purchase, your personal information will be retained indefinitely.

## What rights you have over your data

You may opt-out of receiving most e-mails from us by following the “unsubscribe” instructions provided in the e-mails. Alternatively, you may contact us as described herein. If you are our customer, you may not be able to opt out of all emails, including certain administrative or billing communications which are important to the ongoing maintenance of your account.

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, subscribed to an email campaign or purchased a product, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Contact information

If you have privacy concerns, you can contact the website owner directly via the following web form: https://machinelearningmastery.com/contact/

Or send a letter to:

Machine Learning Mastery Pty. Ltd.  
PO Box 206  
Vermont Victoria 3133  
Australia
